# **Nicolas Trinephi**

**♀** Irvine, California □ +1(949)-329-3603

nicolas@trinephi.com
ntrin.github.io

/in/nicolastrinephi
/ntrin

**SUMMARY** 

Master's graduate in computational science with industry experience in deep learning algorithms applied to time series prediction using cloud data flow tools such as Databricks. Proficient in Python and C++ object oriented programming, I always strive to exceed targets, work efficiently and communicate effectively.

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science: Applied Computational Science

Sept 2019 - Sept 2020

Imperial College London - London, UK

- Relevant Coursework: PyTorch Classification and Transfer Learning, Machine Learning, Optimisation, Numerical Methods, C++ Advanced Programming
- Thesis title: Deep Learning in Virtual Flow Metering

**Bachelor of Engineering (Hons)**: Mechanical Engineering with Finance *University College London - London, UK* 

Sept 2016 - July 2019

• Thesis title: Particle Suspensions in Microfluidic Applications

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Graduate Teaching Assistant**: Applied Computational Science *Imperial College London - London, UK (Remote)* 

Sept 2020 - Present

- Supported student learning by holding office hours to explain solutions, methods and key concepts of programming and machine learning.
- Maintained academic excellence through coaching 10 students on work habits and mental health with one-on-one meetings.

Data Science Intern June 2020 - Sept 2020

Wintershall DEA - Hamburg, Germany

- Streamlined project management and decision making by performing statistical and bi-variate analysis of 13 years of raw industrial oil production data on Azure Databricks using Apache PySpark.
- Designed interactive visualization of the data in Python using Plotly and HVplot for more effective data comprehension and analysis.
- Successfully forecast production rates with RMSE <1% by applying various LSTM recursive neural networks using Keras and monitoring the life cycle with MLflow.
- Formally communicated forecast results by presenting company-wide L3 presentation.

### **Primary Mentor**

May 2019 - July 2019

UCL MechSpace - London, UK

- Coached students on design and technical platforms such as CAD and ARDUINO systems which ensured the success of projects such as the Hydrone Hydrogen Racecar.
- Oversaw the safety of the workshop by supervising working students, facilitating machine operations, and training students in processes such as 3D printing and laser cutting.

# **PROJECTS**

CIFAR-10 *Py* 2020

 Placed in the top 10 (categorization Accuracy 0.8) by applying PyTorch transfer learning with EfficientNet to classify over 10,000 images in a school Kaggle competition.

### Conway's Game of Life in Parallel C++

2020

• Implemented Game of Life in parallel using C++ MPI and object oriented programming wherein the number of cores is user-configurable with a post processing script developed in Python.

### Micro-Particles Image Processing Matlab

2019

• Processed over 2000 images using self-written MATLAB border contour, filling and counting scripts and analyzed results using particle suspension rheology theory.

## **SKILLS**

Languages Native English and French, conversational Spanish

Programming Python, C++, MATLAB, Bash, LATEX, HTML, MySQL, Dox BAT

Packages Keras, PyTorch, PySpark, MLflow, sklearn, XGBoost, Plotly, HoloViews, C++ MPI

Technical Databricks, Apache Spark, Microsoft Office, GitHub, CATIA V. 5, Origin Pro